multicare.org 2018-08-28

# Privacy Policy | MultiCare Health System

### Web Privacy Statement

MultiCare respects the privacy of visitors to this web site and is committed to making the best effort we can to safeguard your information. This statement outlines how we collect, use and protect the personal information you provide to us, and serves to assist you in making informed decisions when using our site and services. Please read this entire statement to understand how your information will be treated.

This statement only applies to the use of information about users of our web site. For information about MultiCare's general privacy policies, please see our [Notice of Privacy Practices](/patient-privacy/). Due to the nature of electronic communications, please understand that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online (i.e. via email), we cannot and do not provide any assurances that your information will not become known or accessible to third parties. If you provide any confidential information about you or your health to us via electronic communication, it is at your own risk. Please be careful and responsible whenever you are online.

### Server Log Information

MultiCare collects standard server log information such as IP address, time spent on the site, browser type, etc. We collect and assess this information on an aggregate basis in order to track site statistics, pages that are most popular to our visitors, performance monitoring and troubleshooting. We also use this information for site and system security. We do not share server log information with third parties for marketing or other purposes.

### Registration Information

Any registration form that requires a visitor to provide us with contact information (i.e. name, address, phone number), unique identifiers (i.e. email address, social security number), financial information (i.e. account or credit card numbers), and other information (i.e. employment history, preferences, etc.) is covered in this privacy policy. Financial information that is collected is used only to bill the visitor for services and products utilized. Unique identifiers (i.e. social security numbers) are collected only for registration and educational class enrollment. Access to this information is password protected on our servers, and is accessible to only a minimal number of MultiCare employees for business use only. We do not share this information with outside parties.

### Security

MultiCare has security measures in place to prevent the loss, misuse or alteration of information under our control. MultiCare employs strict security measures to safeguard online transactions through the use of Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) with 128-bit encryption. Any connection between your web browser and an https-protected page on our site uses this level of encryption. Learn more about [MyChart Security Settings](/mychart-security/).

### Email

Transmittal of emails to this web site may not be private. Whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online (i.e. via email), we cannot and do not provide any assurances that your information will not become known or accessible to third parties. If you provide any confidential information about you or your health to us via electronic communication, it is at your own risk. MultiCare employs strict security measures to safeguard information, but no site has been proven to be impenetrable.

### Opt In/Out

We may ask for additional information in order to offer materials of interest to individuals with specific needs. We offer an opt in/out option which is stored with your account. We will continue to send information to you as long as you opt to receive it.

### Cookies

MultiCare's web site may use cookies in specific areas for statistical tracking purposes, to store visitor preferences, and to assist in the personalization of a display. A cookie is information that a web site puts on your computer's hard drive so that it can remember something about you at a later time. Typically, a cookie records your preferences when using a particular site.

### Links to Other Sites

MultiCare's web site contains links to other websites as a service to our visitors. MultiCare, its members and affiliates are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of these externally sponsored websites. When you leave MultiCare's site, we encourage you to read the privacy statement of any other site that you visit. MultiCare uses [survey software](https://www.surveygizmo.com/) powered by SurveyGizmo.

### Disclaimer

The content provided by MultiCare is for general information purposes only and is in no way intended to be a substitute for medical consultation with a qualified professional. MultiCare encourages internet users to be careful when using medical information. If you are unsure about your medical condition, consult a physician. Although we carefully review our content, we cannot guarantee or take responsibility for the medical accuracy of the content we provide, nor can MultiCare assume any liability for the content of web sites linked to our site.

Although every effort is made to keep this web site updated, neither MultiCare nor any employee or contractor warrants the accuracy, reliability, or timeliness of any information published on this web site or any site that links to or is linked from this web site. MultiCare shall not be held liable for any losses caused by reliance on the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of such information. Any person or entity that relies on any information obtained using this web site does so at his or her own risk. MultiCare may make changes to the information contained on this web site at any time, without notice.

### Contact Us

If you have any questions about our privacy statement, security practices, or would like to be removed from our mailing lists, please contact us:

253-403-2708

MultiCare Health System  
Attn: Customer Service  
P.O. Box 5299  
Tacoma, WA 98415-0299
